I've had enough. Piloting the Eva, being at NERV — I hate all of it.
もう嫌だ。エヴァに乗るのも、ネルフにいるのも、全部嫌だ。
Shinji Ikari is missing. He's not at home, school, or headquarters.
碇シンジが行方不明です。自宅にも学校にも本部にもいません。
Deploy a search team. Check surveillance camera footage across all of Tokyo-3.
捜索班を出せ。第三新東京市全域に監視カメラの映像を確認しろ。
Without a pilot, we won't be able to respond when the next Angel arrives.
パイロットがいなければ、次の使徒が来た時に対応できません。
Proceed with arrangements for an alternate pilot. What is the status of Unit-00's pilot, Rei Ayanami?
代替パイロットの手配を進めろ。零号機のパイロット、綾波レイの状態はどうだ？
Ayanami is still recovering from severe injuries. I assess that combat deployment is impossible.
綾波は重傷からの回復途中です。実戦投入は不可能と判断します。
Nobody needs me. Not Father. Not anyone.
僕は誰からも必要とされていない。父さんにも、誰にも。
It started raining. Where should I go? I have no place to return to.
雨が降ってきた。どこに行けばいいんだろう。帰る場所なんてない。
I got on a train, thinking I'd go as far away as possible. But I didn't know which station to get off at.
電車に乗って、どこまでも遠くに行こうと思った。でも、降りる駅が分からなかった。
If I don't pilot it, someone else gets hurt. But I don't want to be hurt anymore.
僕が乗らなければ、他の誰かが傷つく。でも、僕はもう傷つきたくない。
I want to run away, but there's nothing waiting wherever I run. In the end, this is the only place I have.
逃げ出したいのに、逃げた先にも何もない。結局、僕にはここしかないのか。
Report from NERV Security. Shinji Ikari located on the outskirts of Tokyo-3.
ネルフ保安部より報告。碇シンジ、第三新東京市郊外で発見。
Shinji... you came back.
シンジ君…帰ってきたのね。
I'm home... though I'm not sure if I'm allowed to say that.
ただいま…って言っていいのか分からないけど。
Welcome home.
おかえりなさい。
I still don't know why I pilot the Eva. But for now, I want to be here.
僕はまだ、エヴァに乗る理由が分からない。でも、今はここにいたい。
If you chose to stay of your own will, then that's enough.
自分の意志で残ることを選んだのなら、それでいい。
Shinji Ikari, returning to duty as pilot. Please begin preparations to reactivate Unit-01.
碇シンジ、パイロットとして復帰します。初号機の再起動準備を開始してください。
Eva Unit-01, all systems nominal. Synchronization rate... it's higher than before.
エヴァ初号機、全システム正常。シンクロ率…以前より上昇しています。
People can't live alone. But being with others is frightening too. Even so, you have no choice but to keep moving forward.
人は一人では生きていけない。でも、他人と一緒にいるのも怖い。それでも前に進むしかない。